Well, I'm sure you're fed up of me saying that the moment of truth has arrived, but it really has.
제가 이런 말 하는 게 지겹겠지만 진실의 순간이 왔어요
The moment of truth has arrived.
진실의 순간이 왔어요
I'm extremely excited, as you could probably tell, and I hope you are too.
보시다시피 전 정말 흥분돼요 여러분도 그렇길 바라요
This is this is a big deal, a big, a big moment for us.
이건 저희에게 아주 중요한 순간이에요
So first of all, we are in the week seven day three Colab, and I must confess that I'm doing something
콜랍 비트를 7일간 사용하고 있는데요 솔직히 말하면 좀 야한
a bit naughty in that I have picked a super beefy A100 GPU box, which is the most pricey of the Colab
걸 준비했어요 아주 우람한 A100 GPU 박스를 골랐죠 콜랍 박스에서 가장 비싼 제품이에요
It gobbles up 11.77 uh units compute units per hour, and I think the current going rate, if I'm if
11점을 기록하네요 시간당 계산 단위 77개 현재 시세는 제가 잘못
I'm not mistaken, um, it's roughly 100 units cost about $10.
안 게 아니라면 약 100개 단위 약 10달러네요
So this is this is spending about a dollar an hour.
시간당 1달러 정도를 쓰는 거예요
Um, right now those prices do change from time to time.
지금은 가격이 때때로 바뀌어요
Um, so, yeah, This is this is definitely not as cheap as as things usually are.
네, 이건 확실히 평소보다 싸지 않아요
And you don't need to do this.
이럴 필요 없어요
You can definitely use a, um, let me see.
꼭 필요한 건 어디 보죠
Uh, change runtime type.
런타임 타입을 변경하세요
You can be using a t4 GPU.
t4 GPU를 사용할 수도 있어요
I will tell you which parameters to change for that and it will be just fine.
어떤 매개 변수를 변경할지 알려드릴게요, 괜찮을 거예요
Um, but if you don't mind spending a few dollars and you want to have a blast and you want to be changing
하지만 몇 달러만 써도 블래스트를 경험하고 하이퍼 매개변수를
hyper parameters and training fast, it's beautiful to have an A100 box for a while and experience the
바꾸고 빠르게 훈련하고 싶다면 A100 박스를 사용하면 됩니다 GPU
raw power of a box with 40GB of GPU Ram, so I love it.
40GB가 있는 박스의 힘을 경험해보세요
I don't I I don't mind giving Google a little bit of money for this, because it's a it's such a treat
구글에 돈을 좀 쥐여줘도 괜찮아요 이렇게 즙이 많고
to have a juicy, powerful box like this.
강력한 비트 박스가 있잖아요
So anyways, we start with some pip installs.
어쨌든 파이프 설치부터 시작할게요
This includes this library TRL Transformers Reinforcement Learning from Huggingface, which contains
TRL 트랜스포머 강화 학습 프로그램인 HINGPace 라이브러리도 포함됩니다
the SFT trainer supervised Fine Tuning Trainer, which is the trainer that we'll be doing the work for
SFT 트레이너가 감독한 파인 튜닝 트레이너로 오늘 저희가 할 트레이너죠
Um, and I do want to say I should take just a moment to say that I talked, uh, in the last video,
잠시 드릴 말씀이 있는데요 지난 비디오에서 훈련에 관해
um, a fair bit about training, and I, I sort of did it almost by the by, I talked about about some
조금 다뤘습니다 비트를 통해 하이퍼파라미터도
of the hyperparameters and in doing so talked about a bit of the training process of forward passes
언급했고 전후 패스 훈련 과정도 조금 다뤘죠
And again, for some people, that's old hat that you're very familiar with this.
어떤 사람들은 그런 게 익숙할 거예요
For some people that might have gone over your head and you might be be be saying, you know, can you
어떤 사람들은 당신의 머리 위에 있는 것을 요구할 수도 있습니다. HDTT를
not take more time to better explain the whole training process?
더 잘 설명하기 위해 시간을 더 들이지 않을 수 있나요?
And one thing I do want to say is that hugging face has made this so accessible, so easy.
한 가지 말씀드리고 싶은 건 포옹하는 얼굴 덕분에 이 과정이 아주 쉬워졌다는 거예요
Um, they've made the barrier to entry for training a model so low that whilst it's very helpful to
훈련에 있어서 진입 장벽이 너무 낮아서 직관력을 발휘하는
have an intuition for what's going on in terms of, of of optimizing, of taking steps in the right
게 도움이 되긴 해요 최적화하고 올바른 방향으로 나아가는
direction, this is helpful.
직관력요
It's not essential to know the detail of the theory.
이론의 세부 사항을 알 필요는 없어요
Uh, you just have to know enough to be able to tweak the hyperparameters.
하이퍼파라미터 조정할 만큼만 알면 돼요
Parameters.
매개 변수요
Hugging face makes it incredibly easy to do the training.
얼굴을 끌어안으면 훈련이 아주 쉬워져요
So if you did feel like some of that went over your head, then rest assured it really doesn't matter.
만약 어떤 것들이 여러분 머리 위를 지나갔다고 생각하신다면 걱정하지 마세요. 중요하지 않아요. HET
The code will make it very clear.
코드가 아주 명확할 거예요
And if you know this stuff back to front already and you're very familiar with optimization, then great.
이미 이 모든 걸 알고 최적화에 익숙하다면 아주 좋아요
That will make it so much the better.
그럼 훨씬 더 좋겠죠
It'll make it even easier.
그럼 더 쉽겠죠
All right, so we do some some imports.
수입을 좀 해 보죠
And now we have a bunch of parameters to talk about.
이제 매개 변수가 많이 생겼죠
So uh, the base model of course llama 3.18 billion.
기본 모델은 당연히 라마 3이고요 180억 달러요
We know it well the project name.
프로젝트 이름은 잘 알죠
So this is the project name that will be used in weights and biases.
무게와 편향에 사용될 프로젝트 이름이에요
Uh, when we get to that, to, to show the, the, uh, the results that will compare.
Get을 하면 비교할 수 있는 결과를 보여줄 거예요
And we'll also use it when we upload to the Hugging Face hub.
H깅 페이스 허브에 업로드 할 때도 사용할 거예요
And I'm using the name Pricer for this project, as in something that comes up with prices.
이 프로젝트에선 프라이서란 이름을 사용하고 있어요 가격과 관련된 뭔가처럼요
You may remember when we were training a GPT, I called it Pricer GPT.
기억하실지 모르겠지만 GPT를 훈련할 때 프라이서 GPT라고 불렀어요
I've kept the project separate because the results will be so different That just because we'll be measuring
결과가 다를까 봐 프로젝트를 분리해 뒀어요 다른 양을 측정할 거라서 같은
different quantities, it will be confusing to have them in the same project.
프로젝트에 두면 헷갈릴 수 있거든요
Um, so, uh, I've called this just pricer.
그래서 프라이서라고 이름 지었어요
Uh, hugging face user, you should put your hugging face name in here.
아, 안는 얼굴 사용자요 여기에 안는 얼굴 이름을 넣으세요
Uh, because you'll be wanting to post push your fine tuned models to the hub for your models because
정밀 튜닝 모델을 허브에 post 하고 싶을 테니까요. 왜냐하면 여러분이 그것들을 소중히 여기고 미래에
you will treasure them and use them in the future.
사용하게 될 테니까요.
And you can keep them private.
비밀로 간직할 수 있어요
Uh, they're just for your own consumption.
그냥 여러분이 드실 거예요
So when it comes to the data, we need to load in the data set.
데이터에 관해서는 데이터 세트를 로드해야 해요
And here you that you have a choice.
여기선 선택할 수 있어요
If a few weeks ago when we were doing data curation, you did go all the way through and you uploaded
몇 주 전에 데이터 큐레이션을 할 때 데이터 세트를 포옹 페이스 허브에 업로드했죠
the data set to your Hugging Face hub, then you can keep this line in here and it will have your hugging
이 선을 여기 둘 수 있어요 포옹 페이스 사용자 이름과 프라이서 데이터죠
face username and then pricer data, which is what we we called it, and you'll be able to load it in.
우리가 부르는 이름이에요 로드할 수 있어요
Alternatively, if you decided just to watch that one out and watch me doing the data set stuff but
아니면 그냥 이걸 보면서 데이터셋 작업하는 걸 보든지요 허깅페이스에
you didn't, uh, upload it to Huggingface then then.
업로드 안 한 거요
Shame.
안타깝네요
But still, I do understand there was quite a lot to it.
그래도 많은 일이 있었다는 건 알아요
You can simply uncomment this line where I've just hardcoded.
하드코딩한 이 라인을 주석 처리 해제할 수 있어요
We don't need the f there.
F는 필요 없어요
Uh, we've just I've just hard coded the the the price of data in my hub, which will be made public.
하드 코드화 했어요 허브에 데이터 가격을요 공개될 거예요
So you can just download it there for.
그냥 다운로드 하세요
Fine.
좋아요
You don't need to upload your own one.
직접 업로드 안 해도 돼요
And then maximum sequence length, you'll remember the data is always crafted so that it's no more than
최대 시퀀스 길이는 데이터가 항상 조각되어서 179개의 토큰을
179 tokens, adding on a few tokens for the start of sentence and anything any gumph at the end, uh,
넘지 않게 됩니다 문장 시작에 토큰 몇 개를 더하고 끝에 검프한 것을 추가하면
means that we're going to say maximum sequence length of 182.
최대 시퀀스 길이는 182개가 되죠
And this is very important because every training data point will be fitted into this.
이건 아주 중요해요 모든 훈련 데이터 포인트가 여기에 맞물리거든요
So that and this needs to be a small enough number to fit in our GPU's memory.
GPU 메모리에 들어갈 만큼 작은 숫자여야 하죠
And that's why we've cut off our descriptions to fit within this amount.
그래서 이 정도 양에 맞게 설명을 잘라낸 거예요
So then a few, uh, sort of administrative things, um, I've come up with something called the run
몇 가지 관리적인 것들을 살펴봅시다 각 실행의 실행 이름이라는 것을 생각해 냈습니다
name for each of these runs, which is quite simply the current date the year.
간단하게 현재 날짜를 나타내는 것이죠
Month.
한 달요
Day and hour.
낮과 시간요
Minute.
1분
Second.
두 번째요
Right now of this run and you'll see why in just a second.
잠시 후에 그 이유를 알게 될 거예요
I'm going to have something called the Project Run name, which is Pricer, and then a hyphen, and
프로젝트 Run name이라고 입력할게요 Pricer요
then the date, and then the hub model name where I want to save the model will be the username.
그다음 하이픈, 날짜 허브 모델 이름을 입력하죠 모델을 저장하려는 건 사용자 이름이 될 거예요
And then this here.
그리고 이거요
Uh.
네
And why am I doing this.
왜 이걸 하냐고요?
So sometimes people like to just have one model.
그래서 사람들은 모델을 한 명만 쓰기도 해요
And as you run this you just upload different versions that you store against that same model repository.
실행하면 같은 모델 리포지토리에 저장한 다른 버전을 업로드만 하면 되죠
Because remember everything in Huggingface is just a git repo.
허그페이스에서 하는 건 전부 깃 회수예요
So you could just keep um, you could basically just keep pushing new versions of your model that will
그러니까 여러분은 여러분의 모델의 새 버전을 계속 푸시할 수 있는 겁니다 그것의
just be, uh, just new versions of that, like, like checking in new versions of code or pushing versions
새 버전이 되는 거죠 코드의 새 버전을 확인하거나 버전의 코드를 푸시하는 것처럼요
of code.
모델 이름은 같지만 모델의 다른 버전일 수도 있죠
But I quite like to separate out my different runs and have them as different models, because within
하지만 저는 다른 실행을 분리해서 다른 모델로 두는 걸 좋아합니다 그 안에 다른
them there'll be different versions, potentially as different epochs.
버전이 있으니까요 다른 시대로서도 가능하고요
And I like to keep them separate because I'll have trained them with different hyperparameters, and
저는 분리하는 걸 좋아해요 다른 hyperperameter로 훈련했으니까요
I want to keep notes of that.
그걸 기록하고 싶어요
So that's, that's the way I like to do it.
전 이렇게 하는 게 좋아요
Um, not strictly necessary, but I find it helpful.
꼭 필요한 건 아니지만 도움이 될 거예요
Uh, and just to give you a sense for that, if I just take some if I take the run name, let's start
그에 대한 느낌을 드리기 위해 run name을 선택해보죠 그것부터
with that.
시작하죠
If I just show you what run name is right now.
지금 실행 이름을 보여드릴게요
Um, the run name you can see is just the current date that I'm doing this the 22nd and the current
여기 보이는 실행 이름은 현재의 날짜입니다 22일과 현재 시간이죠
That time is in UTC in universal time.
우주 시간으로 이루어진 협회의 시간이죠
I'm not actually, it's not actually four minutes past midnight.
사실 지금은 12시 4분이 아니에요
Uh, so that's the run name.
그게 실행명이에요
And then what was the other thing?
또 뭐가 있었죠?
Uh, there's project run name and then hub model name.
프로젝트 실행 이름과 허브 모델 이름이 있네요
So project run name is just Pricer followed by that.
프로젝트 실행 이름은 Pricer로 하고요
And then hub model name, which is what it will be uploaded as.
그리고 업로드 될 허브 모델 이름이죠
Is that so?
그래요?
This will be creating a model with that name after it's run.
실행된 후에 그 이름으로 모델을 생성할 거예요
And so if when I look in my models directory, I see a bunch of these because I've run this too many
모델 디렉터리를 보면 이런 게 잔뜩 보여요 너무 많이 실행했거든요 인정하는
times, more times than I'm willing to admit.
것보다 더 많이요
Uh, but it's been great fun.
하지만 정말 즐거웠어요
Uh, I've got lots of these pricer models.
프라이서 모델은 많아요
Uh, and they've all been running.
전부 도망치고 있어요
Uh, so just to finish this off, um, I see it just disconnected and reconnected over there.
이제 마무리할게요 방금 연결됐다가 끊겼다가 하네요
Uh, so the hyperparameters then that we are using for training, uh, you know, are, well, the dimensions
훈련에 사용하는 하이퍼파라미터는 매트릭스의 차원이에요
Um, and I'm starting with 32.
32명부터 시작할게요
As I say, you can bring that down to eight.
아까 말했듯이 8명까지 줄일 수 있어요
Uh, particularly if you're running on a lower box.
특히 로우 박스라면요
It'll be just fine.
괜찮을 거예요
Uh, Laura, Alpha should be double R.
로라, 알파는 더블 R이에요
Um, and so if you bring this down to eight, then make this 16.
이걸 8로 내리면 16이 되는 거죠
Um, the target modules, of course.
물론 목표 모듈이죠
Are you know it too well.
너무 잘 아시네요
I don't need to tell you what they are.
그게 뭔지는 말 안 해도 알겠죠
And this is the standard ones for the llama three.
이건 라마 3의 기본 모델이에요
These are the modules that you target.
이 모듈이 목표예요
The Lora dropout was the thing that I gave quite the long explanation of last time.
로라 중퇴는 지난번에 꽤 길게 설명한 거예요
It's the the the trick to help with regularization, or with making sure that models generalize well
정규화에 도움이 되는 방법입니다 새로운 데이터 포인트에 모델이 일반화되도록 하는
to new data points by taking 10%, in this case 10% of the neurons, and just wiping them out, setting
거죠 이 경우에는 10%의 뉴런을 가져다가 활성화되지 않게 하고 완전히 지워버리는
their activations to zero, effectively just removing them from the training process a different 10%
겁니다 훈련 과정에서 매번 다른 10%씩 뉴런을 제거하는 거죠
And as a result, the model doesn't become overly dependent on any one neuron.
그 결과, 모델은 특정 뉴런에 지나치게 의존하지 않아요
It just learns to generally for the whole model to get better at receiving training points and giving
전체 모델을 향상시키기 위해 전반적으로 학습합니다. 훈련 포인트를 받고 올바른 다음 토큰을
the right next token so it helps the model generalize.
주는 것을요. 모델이 일반화되도록 돕죠.
10% is 10.1 is a very typical starting point.
10%도 10이에요 1은 아주 전형적인 출발점이에요
You should try 5% and 20% and see how they perform and quant for bits.
5%와 20%로 해보고 퀀트 포 비츠로 어떻게 하나 봐요
True.
맞아요
Is is quantizing down to four bits.
4분의 1로 수량화하고 있어요
Okay.
네
The hyperparameters for hyperparameters for training.
hyperperameter를 위한 hyperperameter 훈련용으로요
I've set this up to run for three epochs.
세 개 개 개혁에 사용할 계획이에요
You could do it just for one.
한 명만 해도 돼요
By all means, you'll have perfectly decent results after one batch size.
한 번 만든 양이면 완벽한 결과가 나올 거예요
I've got to 16 right here.
1만 6천 달러예요
Uh, I would, would you need it with.
같이 필요하실 것 같아요
With, um, a juicy A100 box?
끝내주는 A100 박스로요?
I can pack in a batch size of 16 batches.
16번씩 포장할 수 있어요
Given that this is the max sequence length, it can cram all of them in and still have just about squeeze
이게 최대 시퀀스 길이인 걸 고려하면 전부 밀어넣을 수 있어요 40GB 메모리에
that into the 40GB of memory.
겨우 넣을 수 있죠
Um, but for for for you, if you're going to go with a lower end box like a T4, then this should be
하지만 T4처럼 낮은 박스를 사용하고 싶다면 이 제품을 사용해
probably one you could try.
보는 게 좋을 거예요
Try it higher.
더 높이 해봐요
If you get more GPU memory that's still free.
GPU 메모리가 더 많으면 get get은 여전히 공짜죠
Um, there's this convention that people tend to use powers of two for batch size.
배치 사이즈를 위해 파워 2를 쓰는 게 관례예요
So one or 2 or 4 or 8 or 16.
1, 2, 4, 8, 16명이요
Um, and in theory, there's a there's various loose bits of evidence that suggest that if you have
이론상으로는 2의 제곱으로 설정했을 때 GPU 성능이
it as a power of two, the GPU is better able to parallelize it, and the the performance is slightly
더 좋아진다는 여러 가지 불확실한 증거가 있는데요
Um, but there's always the data on that is, is always, uh, just a little bit vague.
하지만 비트에 관한 데이터는 항상 좀 모호해요
And so generally speaking, I imagine if you can cram another a little bit more batch, uh, onto your
일반적으로 말하자면 GPU 위에 좀 더 많은 비트를 밀어 넣을 수 있다면
GPU, then you should do so.
그렇게 해야죠
So I wouldn't shy away from having a batch size of three.
그래서 3개 분량도 주저 없이 만들 수 있어요
If you can fit that on your GPU, it's going to run faster than a batch size of two.
GPU 안에 넣을 수 있다면 배치 크기 2보다 더 빨리 실행될 거예요
Uh, maybe maybe four would would just be that little bit more, be a bit more efficient if it could
비트가 더 잘 맞는다면 4개가 더 효율적일 거예요
fit.
일반적으로 권고하자면 GPU 크기에 맞는 걸 선택해서 그걸로 시작하고
with one and see what kind of headroom you have.
상당한 공간을 확보하세요
Unless you're splashing out like me, in which case go for 16 gradient accumulation steps.
저처럼 돈을 펑펑 쓰실 게 아니라면 16단계 그러데이션 누적 과정을 거치세요
I explained that last time.
저번에 설명했잖아요
I think actually this helps with the improve the memory of the process.
메모리 증진에 도움이 되는 것 같아요
Uh, you could try, but But I'm staying with one.
그래도 되지만 전 한 명과 함께 지내고 있어요
You can try that at 2 or 4 as well.
2-4시에 시도해 보세요
Learning rates I think you know understand is super important is how much of a step you take as you
학습률은 정말 중요합니다 올바른 방향으로 나아가기 위해 최적화할 때
optimize to try and take a step in the right direction.
얼마나 걸음을 내딛는지가 중요하죠
And learning rate is a super important hyperparameter that you need to experiment with.
학습률은 실험해 봐야 할 아주 중요한 하이퍼파라미터예요
Um, and it's one of those things which which, uh, there's no right answer.
그리고 이런 질문에는 정답이 없어요
Learning rate could be too high or it could be too low.
학습률이 너무 높거나 너무 낮을 수 있어요
The what you're trying to achieve this is going to be a bit hand-wavy.
손으로 물결무늬를 만들 거예요 비트를 입어요
Again, what you're trying to achieve is, if you imagine that the loss, uh, the true the loss of
다시 말씀드리지만 여러분이 이루고자 하는 것은 모델이 사라졌다고 가정해
your model, uh, is something which has a big dip in it like this.
보세요 이렇게 크게 움푹 들어간 부분이죠
And you're trying to find this valley, you're trying to locate this valley.
이 계곡을 찾고 저 계곡을 찾아야 해요
Then you want to be taking these steps, uh, along the direction of the valley, dropping so that you
이 계단을 오르다가 골짜기 방향을 따라 내려가면 골짜기
will end up at the bottom of this valley.
바닥에 닿을 거예요
If your learning rate is too high, you might jump over that valley and jump back again and never actually
학습 속도가 너무 높으면 계곡을 넘었다 다시 돌아와야 해요 계곡 아래로 내려가면
go down into the valley.
안 되죠
If your learning rate is too low.
학습률이 너무 낮으면요
You might take little tiny steps and be making two slower progress towards that valley.
작은 걸음을 내디디면서 계곡으로 가는 속도가 느려질 수도 있어요
There's another problem with taking two small steps.
작은 보폭 두 개에는 또 다른 문제가 있어요
Supposing that you don't just have one big valley, but you have a smaller valley and then the big valley.
하나의 큰 계곡이 아니라 작은 계곡이 있고 큰 계곡이 있다고 가정해 보죠
If your learning rate is too low, you might take small steps and end up sinking down into that little
학습률이 너무 낮으면 작은 발걸음을 떼다가 저 작은 계곡으로 가라앉을 수도
valley.
있어요
And actually every small step you take just goes up the two walls of the little valley and never gets
작은 걸음을 내디딜 때마다 작은 계곡의 두 벽을 따라 올라가는데 그 계곡을
out of that little valley.
벗어나지 못해요
And so you never realize that there was this much bigger value valley just next door.
그래서 바로 옆에 훨씬 더 큰 밸리가 있다는 걸 전혀 알 수 없죠
And so that is a key problem.
그게 핵심적인 문제죠
It's a common problem with learning rates being too small.
학습 속도가 너무 낮으면 흔한 문제예요
People call it being stuck in the local minimum.
사람들은 그걸 지역 내 최소량에 갇힌 거라고 하죠
This thing is called a minimum and it's local to where you are.
이건 최소라고 하는데 여러분이 있는 곳의 로컬이죠
And you haven't found the the global minimum, which is which is all the way down here because you're
글로벌 최소치를 못 찾았군요 이 아래쪽에 있는 거요 로컬 최소치에
stuck in the local minimum.
갇혀 있으니까요
And that is the problem with having a learning rate that's too low.
학습률이 너무 낮으면 이런 문제가 생겨요
There is this nice trick.
멋진 트릭이 있어요
I picked a learning rate of 0.00011 times ten to the minus four.
학습률은 0으로 정했어요 00011 곱하기 10은 4죠
There's a nice trick of using something called a learning rate scheduler, which is something that will
학습률 스케줄러라는 게 있는데 이 프로그램은 학습률을
vary the learning rate and make it get smaller and smaller and smaller over the course of your three
다양하게 해서 세 개 시대에 걸쳐 학습률을 점점 줄여
epochs, until it's pretty much zero by the end of your three epochs.
줍니다 결국 0이 될 때까지요
Um, and you can give it.
그걸 줄 수 있어요
If you choose to use one of these, you can give it a different shape.
이 중 하나를 선택하면 다른 모양을 줄 수 있어요
And cosine is a very nice one, which starts with a learning rate that starts at the slowly decreases,
코사인은 아주 좋은 제품이에요 학습 속도가 아주 느리게 시작하지만 점차 감소하고
and then it decreases quite a lot.
있어요
And then it tails off at the end.
끝에는 꼬리가 보여요
Uh, you'll see that visually in a moment.
곧 시각적으로 보실 거예요
And that's a really good, good technique.
아주 좋은 기술이에요
Um, and the final learning rate parameter is called the warm up ratio, which is saying at the very
최종 학습률 매개변수는 웜업 비율이라고 하는데요 훈련 과정
beginning of your training process, things are quite unstable because your model has a lot to learn
초기에 모델이 처음 데이터 포인트 몇 개에서 배울 게 많아서 불안정하다는
from the first few data points.
뜻이죠
And it's quite dangerous to have a big learning rate initially because it would jump all over the place.
처음에 학습률이 높으면 위험합니다 모든 게 뒤죽박죽이 되거든요
So warm up ratio says start with a lower learning rate and then warm it up to the learning rate that
워밍업 비율은 낮은 학습율로 시작해서 최고가 될 때까지 워밍업하는
it becomes the peak.
거예요
And then start your cosine, uh, trail.
이제 코사인 트레일을 만들어 보죠
And you'll see that visually.
시각적으로도 볼 수 있어요
So it'll make more sense.
그래야 말이 되죠
But these are these are very sensible settings.
하지만 이건 아주 합리적인 설정이에요
But you can definitely experiment with a higher or lower starting learning rate or different scheduler
하지만 학습 시작률이 높거나 낮거나 다양한 스케줄러 유형을 실험할 수
types.
있어요
And finally the optimizer.
마지막으로 최적화 장치예요
So here I am picking the paged Adam w uh w means with weight decay a paged Adam w 32 bit.
여기 peded Adam w를 선택할게요. W는 무게 감쇠 a peded Adam w 32 비트라는 뜻이에요.
That is a good optimizer, which has good convergence.
융합이 잘되는 최적화 장치죠
It does a good job of finding the the optimal spot, but it comes at a cost of consuming memory.
최적의 장소를 찾는 건 잘하지만 메모리 소모에 따른 대가가 따르죠
Um, I've put down here a link to a hugging face writeup on the different optimizers that you could
여기 링크를 걸어 놨어요 다양한 최적화 방법을 소개한 We't go에 관한 글이에요
Um, it's clear that the most common for Transformers is Adam or Adam.
트랜스포머에 가장 많이 나오는 건 애덤과 애덤이에요
W um, and that Adam, uh, does does do well because it stores the rolling average of prior gradients,
애덤이 아주 잘하네요 이전 평균 그러데이션을 저장하고 있거든요 최근 그러데이션보다
and it uses that rather than just the most recent gradient.
더 잘 활용하고 있어요
But of course, by storing that, that's going to take an extra memory footprint.
하지만 그걸 저장하면 추가 메모리 공간이 필요해요
And so it's a bit greedy for memory.
비트는 좀 과한 메모리예요
So if you're running out of memory then you have an option to choose a cheaper, less greedy optimizer
메모리가 부족하다면 더 싸고 욕심이 덜한 최적화 장치를 선택해 메모리를 저장하세요
But the results might be slightly worse than than using the paged Adam w okay.
하지만 결과는 pageed Adam w보다 약간 나쁠 수도 있어요
And then finally some administrative setup.
마지막으로 행정적인 설정이 있죠
Uh, this number of steps is how many batch steps to take before it.
이 단계의 수는 제조 단계를 나타내요
It saves progress to weights and biases to show us how things are going.
진척을 줄여 무게와 편견을 줄여 현재 상황을 보여 주죠
Um, and this is how many steps before it actually uploads the model to the hub and saves a proper version
이건 몇 단계에 걸쳐 허브로 모델을 업로드하고 적절한 버전을 저장하는 단계죠
This is whether or not we're logging to weights and biases, so that that is a tour of the parameters.
무게와 편향으로 로깅을 하는지 아닌지를 보여줍니다 매개 변수를 보여드린 거죠
And in the next time we really get to to the trainer itself.
다음엔 트레이너에 대해 제대로 얘기해보죠 Get it